I am a fan of Ashito Aoi.
Probably his first in the world.
So there you have it.
No matter where you are, there could be fans listening in.
You should try and watch what you say.
Bye.
Oh, hey.
What's up?
You didn't hear that, did you?
Can I get that lunch?
You said that you had made an extra one.
Can I have it?
Uh.
I've been wondering for a while now, how come you're always so gung-ho about helping me out?
I said I was sorry. It's not like I was eavesdropping or anything.
I took a seat on that bench, and then I heard the old man's voice followed by yours through the window.
Someone said my name, and it's not like I could leave at that point.
So I ended up hearing everything.
You literally just described what eavesdropping is.
Don't you have a match that you should be getting ready for?
Now please leave me alone.
Right, in a sec.
One more thing.
I've been meaning to say thank you for persuading my mom and...
Wait, Noriko?
Oh yeah! That reminds me.
I wanted to tell you the next time we met, your mom is amazing!
You really lucked out.
Trust me on this one.
Your mom and I ended up chatting about you a bunch over the phone.
And from the way she went on about you, I could tell just how much she cared for you and wanted you to be happy.
I know.
You're a good person, Hana.
Huh?
That's what I was gonna say when we met again.
You're a good person.
I know.
Of course you'd respond in such a cute way.
Well, makes sense since you're cute.
Uh...
This whole soccer club thing ain't that bad.
Certainly can't complain about the grub.
Wait, hold on.
What the heck did I even say?
That didn't come out right, but you know what I meant.
So you wanted to know why I helped you?
Huh?
You see, the reason I keep on rooting for you is because you remind me of a certain player.
That person is somebody very important to me.
Whenever I watch you play, it brings me back to when I was his superfan.
It's probably a bit selfish of me, since I'm doing it for my own sake.
Oh.
Really?
I remind you of that guy, huh?
In that case, he's gotta be an awesome player, right?
Mm-hmm.
So, hey, listen.
I've got a little dream of my own.
In the future...
Wait just a second.
Where is my lunch?
Uh, I ate it all.
It was good.
Don't you have an important match soon?
I said you could have one!
Why would you stuff your face right before playing?
I'm telling you it'll be fine!
Stop worrying!
Spin it out right now!
Or else I'll have to take it back!
Get your fingers out of my mouth!
You crazy?
I already ate it!
If you want to go pro, you need to learn to take care of your body!
What's up with that chick?
She's scary.
Today's match will be 7-on-7 between the new youth team players using half the field.
It'll be a 30-minute best-of-one, and offsides rules will still apply.
We don't have enough goalkeepers, so I'll be filling in for today.
This will be fun.
What Fukuda mentioned earlier still stands.
If during this match you show us your worth, you'll be promoted to the A-team immediately.
Each team is instructed to follow a tactic that I come up with.
And while you should stick to the general game plan, the minor details are up to you.
There's no way he's going pro.
I'm not going to let you write me off.
Before I even get to play, I'll show you how wrong you are.
I know you think I don't have a chance, you stone-faced jerk.
But for me, going pro isn't a matter of if, but when.
I won't stop until I'm a professional player.
This isn't a matter of wanting or hoping for it.
I know it's going to happen.
That's why, even if my teammates or coaches don't believe in me, I couldn't care less.
Besides, I already have tons of people rooting for me.
I owe them so much, I can't let them down.
This is my first step to becoming a pro.
Right, here we go!
Time to crush my first youth match and get my ticket straight to the A-team!
Hit.
Score.
I've got a score.
I'll show everybody!
Hey, Yuma!
Pass the ball to me!
I'll show you that I'm the reincarnation of Roberto Baccio!
It doesn't matter that he's still alive!
Man, you are wild!
Give me the ball now!
Over here! Pass it back to me!
No, me! Give it to me!
That's up, Corridor!
Man, two inches lower and I would have made it!
Wow, that was close!
What are you doing, Togashi?
Listen, I know you want to impress the coaches, but you shouldn't shove your own teammate to do it!
I don't know if that's how you did things on your old team, but stop messing around!
Hmm, you don't get it, dude. The only way to really show your stuff in a 30-minute half-field game like this is to score!
Even the defenders need to try to make plays, you know?
That's not a reason to be a jerk!
You shouldn't steal the ball from your own team!
Don't do it again!
Also, you're a defender, so act like one!
Did you hear the sound the ball made when it bounced off the bar?
Let's go!
I'm gonna score!
I have to score a goal!
He got that pass through to me?
The ball came in at just the right angle and speed.
This is no time to be impressed.
If I want to score in a game at this level, I gotta stay focused.
Aoi's just charging down the field? Will he pass it?
Is he planning to do it alone?
Hey! Don't try to dribble it through!
Out to the wing! Let's attack down the wing!
You're a defender, so act like one!
I won't let you do anything that'll mess up my play, Togashi!
You're a defender, just focus on your job!
The coaches are watching! I'll score a goal and show them all!
You better not get in my way!
I don't care if it's egotistical.
I know I'm being selfish, but I can't miss this chance.
So in order to guarantee my spot on the A-team,
I have to break through and score a goal!
Nice one!
Oh, I guess he knows better than to charge right in.
Masako, don't let number two get past you.
And keep your distance.
Yeah, of course.
We have enough people behind the ball.
As long as we can hold the line.
Huh?
What's he doing?
He's just walking.
Wait! Don't fall for it!
Stay back!
Eat that!
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about!
That was an amazing place, you dude!
Wow, I can't believe Ashito actually scored a goal.
But I still don't get what he just did.
What was that?
It doesn't make sense.
Aoi was just aimlessly walking around.
Then, all of a sudden,
he made a break for it.
And he broke through the defensive line like it was nothing.
But how?
How in the world did that work?
Mom, Shun, I did it!
But I'm not done yet!
You better get used to seeing more of that!
Because I'm going to score another 3.86 trillion goals this game!
Bravo, Ashito Aoi!
Bravo, I say!
You truly defy logic!
The red team defended well.
They cut off the other team's shooting opportunities
and plugged all the gaps.
But that changed when Aoi started to walk towards the goal.
It completely threw off their rhythm.
No one would expect a player to start calmly walking forward in that situation.
Their defense didn't know how to respond.
That disruption drew Mosco out of his position in the defensive line,
giving Aoi the chance to blow past him when he moved in too close.
I still can't believe he actually pulled it off.
A play like that is pretty much impossible to accomplish
unless you know exactly how each player on the field is going to move.
Hold on, Tsukishima.
Hmm?
That play, doesn't it feel a little off?
I wouldn't celebrate yet.
Dude, that was amazing!
Ah-ha-ha-ha!
That was a high-level play, especially from you.
So, spill the beans, bro.
When did you come up with it?
Oh.
Oh, right.
To be perfectly honest, I can't remember.
Ashito Aoi, there's no question that he's got some interesting skills,
but he has a critical flaw in his play style,
which will prevent him from moving forward.
You know, for a training game, it's getting pretty intense on the field.
Watch out, Kurada.
The parents over there are getting kind of restless.
Can't blame them.
See, I got scouted, and Ashito made it through the tryouts.
But all you junior youth guys haven't made a single play so far.
You guys gotta get moving.
Otherwise, Mommy and Daddy are gonna be so disappointed in you.
Junior youth club players, you're a bunch of losers as far as I'm concerned.
Masago, switch positions with me.
If I don't put a stop to this now, he'll only annoy me more.
Oh, yeah!
Did you see that gold, you jerk?
I bet you'll try to say that one isn't good enough.
Then I'll have to keep scoring as many as I can!
What amazing power, Togashi!
Couple that with his burst of speed, and he's like a tank!
You've gone far enough!
Don't forget you're a defender!
Pass me the ball and get back!
Good job!
Oh?
Ah, sorry.
Oh, you're asking for it!
I became painfully aware during the tryouts
that I was way behind the other youth players
when it came to my ball handling skills.
That's why, as soon as I got my acceptance letter,
I practiced day and night to get better.
My old soccer club helped me train!
I'll get past you!
You idiot!
What do you think you're doing?
You're pushing your luck if you try to dribble it through!
All you need to do is pass it to me like you did before!
There's no rush here!
We just have to move the ball around
until we find an opening to attack from!
It's how we play soccer!
We gotta work together!
Shit!
Ah!
Owie!
One more!
I'll use my first touch trick!
Then I'll land it right there!
And pass him!
I did it!
Huh?
what how did he predict that damn it ashito point your midsection in the direction you
want to run i think i get it now let's go practice that trick on us until you've got
it down pat we'll do whatever we can to help so you can crush it when you get to tokyo
i'll break through i swear i'll break through oh man you said earlier that ashito has a critical
flaw that'll stop him from going pro you were talking about his handling skills is that correct
i'm curious about that too coach date it seems a little harsh i mean he did already score a goal
it's true his ball handling skills aren't great his reactions are slow and his dribbling is messy
and while i'd say he's got raw skill i'd rank his handling at the bottom of the pack
not again after all that practicing i did and with my friends helping me out damn it
i guess it still wasn't enough i see that's fine by me i'd be disappointed if it was that easy
i'll just work twice as hard from now on but that's something that can be improved with practice
and training didn't you say he was skilled earlier why are you suddenly discounting him entirely
it's tactics the critical flaw in his game is tactics right coach nazumi that is correct
you're as perceptive as ever
come on he got the ball stolen again that makes three times in a row now what's going on he's always
there i can't get past sorry you guys give me one more chance i've got him figured out i'll score a goal
this time it's unfortunate but ashito aoi is unable to incorporate tactics in his place this isn't a
matter of not knowing or not understanding how to use them he just can't he'll only be a liability
to the team sorry i didn't hear what you said i think i was too distracted watching the match
what was it that you were going on about miss kaido electrics i wouldn't want to miss what you have
to say please call me enri kaido and i'd be more than happy to slow down for you hana ichijo
i'm curious about something why are you so adamant about ashito aoi
you must be a soccer super fan isn't that right andre you're always paying us visits not that
we're complaining or anything it's just rare for our sponsors to watch training sessions especially
the youth team ones oh am i being a nuisance no not at all we're glad to have you here
pass it come on dude here i'm open and if we're talking about tactics then tell me where the team's
given detailed instructions before the game uh well coach date told the black team to attack while
the red team was told only to defend against right there that is way too vague tactics are supposed to
be specific instructions from the manager it's stuff like play down the wing or everyone play back and
look the counter-attack right which proves my point he scored even though he wasn't given any
instructions so ashito understands and can use tactics if you ask me he did great that may be
but that's not what we were referring to you're talking about team tactics what it's not the same
thing individual tactics that's what i mean in other words crystallized intelligence
something's up with the junior youth players looks like they're playing a lot closer to each other
than before togashi
you got a lot of nerve could it uh you think you can give me orders now
okay this time for sure wait are we hold up play huh what was kuruta trying to tell me
hey aoi i said hold up play just now you were supposed to keep the ball there
so why did you try to attack oh well the call came so suddenly i got confused i'm sorry bro but the
type of pass should have clued you in it's not that hard if you paid attention to our positioning or
where the ball was coming from our intentions during that play were pretty clear intentions positioning
the type of pass i don't understand what's he talking about
oh man for some reason the promoted junior youth player suddenly kicked it into high gear
if you're gonna push up you gotta do it faster you're falling behind
what did you just say to me you punk
crap what happened none of this makes any sense why are the promoted players doing better all of a sudden
they're adapting their play the black team has realized that ashito aoi can't beat asari one-on-one
so they've tightened up their formation and have switched to using shorter passes to compensate
the red team is adapting too they instantly responded by making their defense even more compact
it's situational awareness players have to be able to think for themselves during matches
and adjust their play accordingly if a player cannot adapt they have no place on a professional team
because of this the ability to think and make choices on the field is drilled into our junior
youth team at a young age look closely only the promoted players have adjusted their play
while the others are barely keeping up as for ashito aoi he still hasn't realized the style of play has
shifted the reason behind it is that he's the kind of player who relies on his intuition
while that may seem good unfortunately he takes it to the extreme he'll occasionally pull off amazing
plays but since it's instinctual he's completely clueless as to how or why he accomplished it
that is his critical flaw because of it he's unable to verbalize what he does
nor can he reliably act as a playmaker that's why he'll never go pro
the situational awareness of a jay youth player already far exceeds that of the average high
school player someone who can't think for themselves will never advance what's going on
why did everybody suddenly start playing differently
i don't know what am i supposed to be doing
there are only five minutes left in the match
and no one's passing the ball to me anymore
you
Next time on Awashi, Night Training.